Guide to the Andrew Forest Muir papers MS 017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series V: Alphabetical subject research files, 1935-1969, 252462
  - Hogg-Swayne Syndicate, 1902, 252730 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    Incorporating papers.
  - Holland Lodge, 252729 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Holley, Mary Ann (Austin), 1784-1846, 252728 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    Notes on Holley in deed records of Galveston County, 1831, 1841.
  - Holman, James Sanders, 1804-1867, 252727 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    Texas colonist, revolutionary soldier, first mayor of the city of Houston, officeholder under the Republic of Texas, President of Southern pacific Railroad Company; notes on his life and career; typescript carbon of AFM article "Who Was the First Mayor of Houston?" (unpublished); correspondence on research.
  - Horsfall, William, 252726 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Houston, TX, 1836-1869 notes, 252725 (Box 53, Folder 1-3)
    Notes taken from printed and manuscript maps, census records, church records, city council minutes, commissioners court minutes (Galveston County), newspapers, monographs, survey collections, deed records, transcript of manuscript account book of Doswell & Adams, commission merchants of Houston (Jan. 25 - May 30, 1838)
  - Houston, TX, topics in, 1830s-1840s, 252724 (Box 53, Folder 4-5)
    Notes on Houston arranged by subject in alphabetical order: Folder 4: Abolitionism, Alamo monument, annexation, ants, apprentices, arachnids, architects, arsenal, astronomy, auctioneers, bakeries, balls, bankruptcies, banks and banking, barbecues, barbers, bars, bathing, Beauchamp Spring, bells, billiards, blacksmithing, boarding, books, brawling, bricks, bridges, buffalo, building, business (state of), butchering, cabinet makers, Capitol, carpenters, cat, cattle, Chamber of Commerce, children, Christmas, church, circus, The Citizen newspaper, City Exchange, City Market, City Riflemen, civil engineers, Civilian newspaper, coal, coffee houses, Colt's revolver, commission merchants, confectioneries, cooks, corn, cotton, counterfeits, county jail, credit, currency, Cushatta (town), customs house. Folder 5: daguerreotypes, dancing, debating, dentists, dinners, distilleries, district court, divorces, dogs, Doswell & Adams merchants, drainage, draying, dry goods, education, electioneering, equipages, estrays, Exchange Bank, exchequer bills, excursions, expresss companies, Fannin Artillery, Fayetteville, females, ferries, fireworks, fishing, flags, fornication, foundries, 4th of July, free Negroes, Freemasons, funerals, furniture, Galveston Island, gambling, game, gardening, German immigrants, German Union, goats, graveyards, grist mills, gullies, guns, gunsmiths
  - Houston, TX, topics in, 1830s-1840s, 252723 (Box 54, Folder 1-3)
    Notes on Houston arranged by subject in alphabetical order. Folder 1: hangings, hardware, Harrisburg (town), Harrisburg County, Harris County, Harris County before Revolution, Harrisburg municipality, health, Hibernia Society, hides & peltries, history, horse racing, horses, hospitals, hotels, household supplies, Houston Dragoons, Houston (beginnings of), Houston (founding of), Houston (growth of), Houston (seat of government), Houston (temporary seat of government 1842), Houston Town Company), H.R. Allen & Co., hunting, ice, ice cream, illumination, Indians, insurance, jewelry, John Carlos & Co., John Huffman & Co., Kelley (Cornelius), Kesler's Arcade, land agencies, land laws, lard oil and stearine factories, lawyers, lethal weapons, Liberty Pole, libraries, liquors, livery stables, loafers, long Row, lotteries, Louisville (once Point Pleasant), lumber, Lynchburg. FOLDER 2: matches, mechanics and workingmen, medicine, merchants' supplies, Mexicans, Mexican Invasions (1842), Milan Guards, militia, milk, milliners, money lending, Morning Star newspaper, Morrell & Tyler, mosquitoes, moss, mud, music, musquito, National Banner, Banner of the Lone Star (newspaper), National Intelligencer (newspaper), national politics, natural history, navigation of Buffalo Bayou and Port of Houston, New Washington, New year's Day, newspapers, nurses, Odd Fellows, oranges, Order of Equal Fellows, oxen, painting, patents, pecans, pedlars, perfumery, Philosophical Society of Texas, phrenology, pictures, Piney Point, Pitkin Guards, planters' supplies, plats, population, post office, poultry, powder magazine, President's house, printing, privies, promissory notes, provisions, Protection Fire Company No.1. FOLDER 3: railroads, rats, religion, rental property, restaurants, roaches, roads, Rockey Well (town), room rentals, Sabbath, saddlery, salesmen, San Jacinto Day, San Jacinto (precinct of), San Jacinto (town of), San Saba Company, sawmill, scavengers, scenery, seafood, seamstresses, 2nd of March, sheep, shinplasters, shoemakers, shorthand, sidewalks, silversmiths, slaves, snakes, soda fountains, spectacles, Spilman's Island, Spring Creek, Spring Creek County, stage lines, steam engines, stoves, streets, subdivisions, Sunday school, swine, tailors, tanyards, Telegraph and Texas Register (newspaper), ten pin alleys, tents, Texas Typographical Association, Texian Democrat (newspaper), theater, Times (newspaper), title, tobacco, tombstones, town lots, translation, treasury notes, trees turtle oil, unemployed, ventriloquists, veterans, visitors, wages, washerwomen, watchmakers, water, wax tallow and honey, W.D. & R.M. Lee, wearing apparel, weather, weeds, Weekly Houstonian (newspaper), Weekly Times (newspaper), whipping and branding, whitesmiths, whittling, whores.
  - Houston, TX, notes, 252722 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Houston, TX, intellectual climate of, 252721 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Houston, TX,: "Who was the first mayor of Houston?" typescript by AFM, 252720 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Houston, Matilda C. (Jesse) Fraser, 1820-1892, 252719 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    Member of British peerage, traveller and author, visitor to the Republic of texas, 1840s.
  - Houston, Sam, 1793-1863, 252718 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    President of the Republic of Texas, governor and senator of the state; notes on his life, career, and business; anecdotes, letters, his views on the secession of Texas and the Civil War; notes on relatives of Sam Houston; correspondence on AFM's research.
  - Houston vs. Perry and Williams, 1846-1849, 252717 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    Case in district court of Travis County (1846-48) concerning settlement of empresario contract of Austin and Williams (1831) under the Republic of Texas; notes on decisions of Texas Supreme Court on the appeal (1848) and new trial (1849).
  - Huston, Felix, 252716 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Ibbotson, Caroline Mary, 252715 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Ibbotson, Edmund, 252714 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Ives, Caleb Smith, 1789-1849, 252713 (Box 55, Folder 3-5)
    Anglican priest, founder of Christ Church, Matagorda (1839), rector at Matagorda until his death in 1849, founder of the Matagorda Academy (ca. 1840); much material on early Episcopal Church in Texas, especially in Matagorda; extensive notes on life and career of Ives and family; correspondence on research; typescripts of Matagorda Parish records; 2 typescript copies with corrections of footnotes for AFM edition of portion of Caleb S. Ives' diary (1842-1843).
  - Jackson, Humphrey, 1790-1834, 252712 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    Irish immigrant to Louisiana, member of Austin's Colony (1823), settler in or around Harrisburg; notes on life and family.
  - Jails, 252711 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    Brief notes on problems of Harrisburg County jail (1838-1840) taken from minutes of county commissioners, newspapers, published letters.
  - Jefferson County, TX - wills in, 252710 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    Includes index, v. A-I: 15 names.
  - Jews, 252709 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    Notes on Jews in Texas (1830s-1870s) taken from contemporary printed sources, newspapers, Federal census, records of land grants, tombstones, state laws, district court records, marriage records, interment records, deed records, congregation minute books and account books, monographs, journal articles, probate records, assessors records, reference works; AFM articles "Lewis A. Levy, the Initiator of Organized Jewry in Texas" and "Lewis A. levy, Pioneer Merchant of Houston" (both unpublished); AFM (?) typescript "Jews and Negroes in the Texas Revolution"; typescript carbon of "The Jews in Houston and Galveston, Texas During the Civil War" by Gary Alan Ratkin (May 1963); correspondence on research.
  - Johnston, Rienzi Melville - notes on papers at Fondren Library, 252708 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Jones, Anson, 252707 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Jones, Lucius H., 252706 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary in Texas (Seguin) in 1850s, chaplain in the Confederate army.
  - Kaauwai, William Hoapili, 252705 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    Notes and typescript of article by AFM on Kaauwai.
  - Kay, Stephen, 252704 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    English Presbyterian minister, visitor to Texas (Galveston) 1860s, converted to Episcopalianism, returned to England late 1865.
  - Kellersberger, Getulius Joseph (Julius), 1821-1900, 252703 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    German immigrant, Confederate engineer at Galveston.
  - Kinney, Henry Lawrence, 1862, 252702 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    Resident of Nueces County, held property in Texas, Illinois, on island of Ruaton, in British Honduras, and Central America.
  - Kirby, J.E., 252701 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Kitcat, Vincent Howard, 252700 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    Diocese of Honolulu
  - Knights of the Golden Circle, 252699 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    Notes on and references to the Knights, 1856-1867, and to George C. Bickley, 1814/15-1867.
  - Kong Yin Tet, 252698 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Kokernot, David Levi, 252697 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    Dutch immigrant, settled in Texas 1830, participant in activities at Anahuac, 1832; revolutionary soldier, schooner captain; notes on Texas navy; correspondence on research; activities of Texas army after San Jacinto; photocopy of typescript of "Reminiscences of David Levi Kokernot" edited by Kent Gardien; photocopy of typescript of a speech "Captain Kokernot" by Kent Gardien (?).
  - Kristenstad, 252696 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    Socialistic settlement in Hood County, TX (ca. 1929-1934) established by Martin Christiansen and others; notes on the settlement taken primarily from deed records.
  - Lamar, Mirabeau Buonaparte, 252695 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    Brief notes
  - Land Commissioners, 252694 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    Survey and abstracts from the Proceedings of Board of Land Commissioners of Harris County, Volume A (January 4, 1838-January 7, 1848).
  - Lane, John Frederic, 252693 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Langworthy, Asahel, 252692 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Law -- Louisiana, 252691 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Laws of Texas, Gammel, 252690 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    AN incomplete survey of various special laws (relief acts and company charters) in volumes 4 and 5 (1853-1866) of H.P.N. Gammel (comp.), The Laws of Texas, 1822-1897; incomplete survey of special and general acts in Gammel, vol. 5; incomplete survey of special laws in Gammel vols. 1 and 2; survey of charters of incorporation in Gammel, vols. 1 and 2 (1835-1846).
  - Law -- Texas, 252689 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    Notes on laws pertaining to wills, probate, inventories, colonial records, inheritance, primogeniture under laws of Spain, Mexico, Republic of Texas; correspondence on research.
  - Law -- Texas, 1913-1914 bills from House of Representatives, 252688 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Law -- Texas, 1913-1914 bills from House of Representatives, 252687 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Lee, Davis J., M.D., 252686 (Box 56, Folder 20)
    Includes photocopies of letters from American Missionary Association collection at Fisk University.
  - Lewis, Eric, Rev., 1902, 252685 (Box 56, Folder 21)
    Died 1941 in Ontario Province, Canada; correspondence on research.
  - Lewis, Samuel Seymour, 252684 (Box 56, Folder 22)
    Brief notes, 1840s. Rector of Christ Church, Mobile, Alabama. Brother-in-law of Caleb S. Ives of Matagorda, TX.
  - Liberia (Church in), 252683 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Libraries, 252682 (Box 56, Folder 24)
    Notes on titles available in various places, 19th century.
  - Looscan, Adele Lubbock (Briscoe) papers, 1820s-1870s, 252681 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    Transcripts and abstracts of documents in the Adele Lubbock (Briscoe) Looscan papers; 2 copies of a genealogy of the Harris family (John Richardson Harris of Harrisburg Co., Texas); notes on papers and letters of the Briscoe family (1820s-1840s); Harrisburg Railroad & Trading Co. (1838); transcripts of deeds of Harris County; life of Andrew Briscoe (1810-1849); life of William P. Harris; shipping notices, letters (1830s-1870s) of the Harris, Birdsall, and Richardson families of Harrisburg County; transcripts of travel tickets by steamers, receipts for Briscoe family.
  - Lubbock, Francis Richard, 1850s, Texas Veterans Association, 252680 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Lubbock, Thomas S., 252679 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - McCormick, Margaret, 252678 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - McCulloch, Ben, 252677 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - McKinstry, George B., 1804-1837, 252676 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    Brief genealogy of the McKinstry family of Brazoria and Galveston Counties. McKinstry, a judge of Brazoria County, presided over the probate will of Stephen F. Austin.
  - Mackintosh, Alexander, 252675 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - McNeel Family, 1850-1880, 252674 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    Census returns of members of McNeel family of Brazoria County (1850, 1860, 1870, 1880) and will of John G. McNeel, Sr. (1801/2-1867)
  - Macomb, David Betton,1793-1837, 252673 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Magruder, John Bankhead, 252672 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Mahan, Phineas Jenks, 1814-1875, 252671 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Mann, Pamela, 1830s, 252670 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    Records of land ownership and residence in TX
  - Mark, Yim Sang, 252669 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Marriages, 252668 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    Notes on various marriages performed in the Houston-Galveston area, 1827-1851, taken from county marriage records. Harris County vols. A, B, C (1837-1854); Jefferson County vols. A, B (1937-1849); Brazoria County, vol. 0 (1829-1846); Galveston County, vol. A (1838-1840); criminal court records of Harris County district court under the Republic of Texas: entries concerning Pamela Mann (1837-1857); entires in Deed Records of Harris County concerning Pamela Mann (1839-1840); district court records of Harris County (criminal) volumes A and B (1837-1839); district court records of Travis County (criminal), volumes A,B,C (1840-1853); immigration records (Brazoria County ?), 1835-1844.
  - Marriages index, 252667 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Marriages, officiants of, 252666 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    Alphabetical index of officiants of marriages covering Galveston, Travis, Brazoria, Jefferson, Austin, Bastrop, Washington, Fort Bend, and Harris Counties (antebellum period).
  - Mason, George, 1829-1893, 252665 (Box 58, Folder 5-6)
  - Masterson family, 1813-1949, 252664 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    Notes on Masterson family of Brazoria and Harris Counties (1813-1949); notes taken from deed records, survey map of Brazoria County, transcripts of letters, veterans papers, journal articles, Harris Masterson papers in Fondren Library, newspapers, cemeteries, monographs, census records, marriage records, probate records, will books, district court minutes.
  - Matawanpkeag, 252663 (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Menard, Peter J., 1808-1861, 252662 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    Colonist and Texas rebel, resident of Galveston, postmaster and alderman, relative of the founder of Galveston.
  - Menken, Adah Isaacs, 1835-1868, 252661 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    Ada B. (Theodore) Menken, American actress and dancer; bibliography of works on Adah Isaacs Menken; notes on marriage and divorce; correspondence on research.
  - Merrill, Frank Wesley, 252660 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Mexico, 252659 (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Milam, Benjamin Rush, 252658 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Milam County, TX, 252657 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscegenation, 252656 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Montgomery County, TX Marriage Records, 1838-1840, 252655 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Moore, Edwin Ward, 252654 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Moore, Lyttleton Wilde, 252653 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Moore family, 252652 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    Brief notes on the family of George Moore of Grayson County, Texas, 1860s, taken from census and deed records. George and Mary Moore, parents of Carrie A. (Moore) Nation.
  - Morgan, James, 1787/8-1866, 252651 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    Settled in Texas in 1830, colonial businessman at New Washington (Morgan's Point).
  - Moyers, G. J., 1861-1865 (published diary of), 252650 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Muir, Annie Jane (James), 252649 (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Muir autobiography note (AFM), 252648 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Muir home: 946 Cortlandt, Houston Heights, 252647 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Muir, James Thomas, estate of, 252646 (Box 59, Folder 13)
  - Muldoon, Michael, 252645 (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - Municipalities, Texas, 1835-1840, 252644 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    Notes on municipal corporations in Texas taken from the plan of the Provisional Government of the Republic of texas; records of the General Council; the selection of officials by the General Council; the sale of lots in Washington, Houston, Hamilton, Fayetteville, Buffalo; fate of Harrisburg; references in newspapers; proposed towns of San Louis (San Luis), Austinia, Beaumont, Bolivar, Houston (Houston County), Liverpool, Monticello, Washington; lists of texas towns in the 1840s and references for descriptions.
  - Murray, Amelia Matilda, 1795-1884, 252643 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    British author, botanist, artist, abolitionist, wrote book on Southern botany, toured Texas and the South in the 1850s.
  - Nation, Carry Amelia, 1846-1911, 252642 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    Prohibitionist of 1900-1911; notes on her life and activities, her friends and relatives; correspondence on research.
  - Newspaper abstracts, 252641 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    Survey of news items in Texas newspapers, late 1820s-1870s.
  - Nicholson, Joseph John, 252640 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Niles, 1821-1905, 252639 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Ochiltree, Tom P., 252638 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Odlum, Benjamin, 1807-1861, 252637 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Oil in Brown County, TX, 252636 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    Notes on early oil well in Brown Co. (ca. 1871-1891) found by Martin Meinsinger of Brownwood, TX, taken from deed records, monographs, and district court records; notes on Meinsinger family of Brown County.
  - "Old Three Hundred", 1823-1836, 252635 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    Notes on "Old Three Hundred" applications for land and grants given within Stephen F. Austin's colonies (1823-1836), particularly in Harris County; Stephen F. Austin's power of attorney; notes on Spanish testmentary law.
  - Order of St. Francis, 252634 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Owen, John, 252633 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary to Texas in 1857, San Augustine and Nacogdoches, died in Galveston.
  - Parmalee, Richard, 252632 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Passmore, William (1850s, Chaplain, TX), 252631 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    Episcopalian priest, missionary at St. Paul's Church (Brownsville, TX) 1851-1854, chaplain at post of Fort Brown (1853-1859), rector of St. Paul's Church (1854-post 1856).
  - Patents in Texas and the Southern U.S., 1817-1861, 252630 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    Taken from reports of the U.S. Commissioner of Patents, newspapers, published diaries, state records, correspondence, journals of the Texas Congress, acts of the Texas Congress, published letter collections.
  - Perry, James Franklin, executor, titles from, 252629 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    Photocopy of deed assigned to J.F. Perry as executor of Stephen F. Austin's colonies in Bastrop County (1838); reproductions of case papers in Houston vs Perry, executor of Austin and Williams (1849) before the Texas Supreme Court.
  - Perry, James Franklin, executor, titles to (copies from Texas General Land Office), 252628 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    Photocopies of deed records pertaining to actions of James Franklin Perry as executor of Stephen F. Austin (1838-1840) in Bastrop and Brazoria Counties; photocopies of deed records pertaining to actions of J.F. Perry as executor of S.F. Austin in Brazoria County (1837-1844).
  - Perry, executor vs. Coles, 252627 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    Transcriptions of case papers of James Franklin Perry as executor of Stephen F. Austin, deceased, vs. Mary E. Coles, administrator, William W. Hill, administrator of John P. Coles, deceased, and Thomas L. Scott and wife et al., hiers at law of John P. Coles (1845-1853) over lands claimed by Austin Estate.
  - Perry vs. Hill and Hill vs. Perry, 1838-1842, 252626 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    Case in district court of Brazoria County (1838) concerning the will of Stephen F. Austin, his heirs, and his executors; decision of the Texas Supreme Court (1842) on the appeal; photocopies and transcriptions of district court and Supreme Court records.
  - Petroleum, 252625 (Box 61, Folder 17)
    Notes on and references to petroleum in Texas newspapers, 1865-1866, 1872.
  - Phillips vs. Hill, William G. and wife, 1848, 252624 (Box 61, Folder 18)
    Photocopy of Phillips et al., vs. William G. Hill and Wife (1848) -- see 3 Tex. 397 (1848); participant Eliza M. Hill was a former sister-in-law of Stephen F. Austin and was involved in litigation concerning the Austin estate.
  - Phillips, John W., 252623 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    Methodist minister at Houston, 1840s, at St. Andrew's Church in Bryan, St. Paul's Church in Navasota, at Columbus and Seguin, later ordained as Episcopalian priest, 1870.
  - Phillips, Zeno, d.1835, 252622 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    Husband (1831-1835) of Eliza M. Hill (sister-in-law of Stephen F. Austin); notes on records of administration of his estate (1837-1848)
  - Pierce, Henry Niles, 252621 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    Episcopalian priest, former Baptist, missionary to Texas, rector at Brenham (1848- ?), rector at Christ Church at Matagorda (ca. 1852-1854), later Bishop of Arkansas (1870 - ?); correspondence on research.
  - Pierpoint, Elizabeth Ellet (Lippincott), Markel Austin Parrott, 1806/7-1857, 252620 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    Wife of ____ Markel, John Austin, Thomas F.L. Parrott, William Pierpoint. material covers her life and her part in litigation in district court (1834-1847) concerning lower half of eastern league of John Austin two leagues (site of city of Houston on Buffalo Bayou).
  - Polk, Leonidas, 252619 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    Episcopalian priest, Bishop of the Southwestern Diocese of the United States (1838), Missionary Bishop of Arkansas; Bishop of Louisiana, Confederate General; notes on his tours to Texas churches (1839, 1842, 1844) and religious career; correspondence on research.
  - Portises vs. Hills, 1848, 1855, 1858, 1868, 252618 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    Photocopy of Portis and Wife et a., vs. William G. Hill et al. (1858); participant Eliza M. Hill was a former sister-in-law of Stephen F. Austin; this case involved the S.F. Austin and J.E.B. Austin Estates; abstract of Portis and Wife and Others v. Hill and Wife and Others, 14 Tex. 69 (1855); abstract of David Y. Portis et ux v. William G. Hill et al., 30 Texas 529 (1868); note on David Y. Portis and Wife v. William G. Hill, Administrator of Eliza M. Hill, Deceased, 3 Tex. 273-274 (1848).
  - Post, Richard Bayley, 252617 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Pratt, Hannibal (Rev., Texas), 252616 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    Episcopalian priest, nephew of Caleb B. Ives, missionary to Anderson, TX in 1854, rector at St. Paul's College (Anderson) in 1855, at St. John's in Columbus and St. James' in LaGrange and at Seguin, 1855-1857.
  - Purdy, Lucius Maro, 252615 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    Episcopalian priest, accompanied Bishop Freeman in Texas, 1846.
  - Railroads, 252601
    - Air Line Railroad Co., 1860s, 252614 (Box 62, Folder 10)